Finding Aid for the Carleton Watkins Collection of Photographs LSC.0599
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Yosemite
  - [The Domes from the Sentinel Dome, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 94; Plate Dimensions: 41 × 52 Matt Dimensions: 47 × 62 Mammoth print 1/4" faded line on RE from TE to BE. All edges cockled. All edges creased. Spot 11-3/4" from RE, 1" from BE. Spot 10-1/4" from RE, 3/4" from BE. Spot 6-5/8" from RE, 1" from BE. Spot 4-1/4" from BE, 1/2" from RE. Spot 6-1/8" from TE, 3/4" from RE. Smudge by TLC of photograph. Spot 3-3/4" from TE, 1/2" from LE. Spot 4-1/2" from TE, 5/8" from LE. Sport 4-3/4" from BE, 7/8" from LE. (Box 16)
  - [Mirror View, North Dome, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 57; Plate Dimensions: 41 × 52 Matt Dimensions: 47 × 62 Mammoth print No visible damage. All edges cockled. All corners creased. RE: spot 1" from BE. TE: small crease & tear 4-3/4" from LE. LE: spot 10-1/4" from TE. (Box 17)
  - [The Domes, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 59; Plate Dimensions: 41 × 52 Matt Dimensions: 47 × 62 Mammoth print No visible damage. All edges cockled. All corners creased. BE: spot 1" from edge, 12-1/2" from LE. General foxing BR. LE: 1" smudge next to photo, 6" from TE. (Box 17)
  - [The Yosemite Valley from Inspiration Point, Mariposa Trail], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 6; Plate Dimensions: 41 × 52 Matt Dimensions: 47 × 62 Mammoth print 4 spots in TC: 1) 13-3/8" from LE & 2" from TE, 2) 12-3/8" from LE & 3-1/8" from TE, 3) 13- 3/8" from LE & 3-3/4 from TE, 4) 13-3/8" from LE & 4-3/4" from TE. 1/2" line of fading on RE from TE to BE. All edges cockled. All corners creased. Stain near BE 5" from LE. Spot on RE, 1/2" from BE. Spot near RE, 6-1/4" from TE. Spot near TE, 7-3/4" from LE. (Box 17)
  - [The Three Brothers, 4480 ft, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 28; Plate Dimensions: 41 × 52 Matt Dimensions: 47 × 62 Mammoth print No visible damage. All edges cockled. All corners creased. BLC loss. BE: stain, 2-1/8" from LE. Line above BE, 2" from LE. BE: stain, 4-3/4" from LE. RE: Line 1/2" from BE. RE: smudge, 8-7/8" from BE. RE: 1/2" line, 12-3/8" from BE. TE: large stain from 3-1/2" to 10-1/2" from RE, runs up to edge of photograph.. (Box 17)
  - [Sentinel, 3270 ft, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 33; Plate Dimensions: 52 × 41 Matt Dimensions: 62 × 47 Mammoth print Small hole 4-1/2" from LE, 3" from TE. 1/4" faded line along BE, from LE to RE. All edges cockled. All edges creased. (Box 17)
  - [Down the Valley, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 37; Plate Dimensions: 41 × 52 Matt Dimensions: 47 × 62 Mammoth print Small surface loss 3-1/2" from TE. Spot 3" from TE, 4-1/8" from LE. Water (?) stain on TE, from 2-1/2" to 9" from RE, 1-1/2" from TE. All edges cockled. All edges creased. Surface loss BLC. Smudges along BE. TE: Stain from 2-3/4" to 12-1/2" from RE, extends down onto photograph as noted above. LE: small stain 1-3/4" from TE. (Box 18)
  - [Mirror View, El Capitan, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 38; Plate Dimensions: 52 × 41 Matt Dimensions: 62 × 47 Mammoth print RE: 1/2" fading from TE to BE. BE: 1/4" fading from LE to RE. All edges cockled. All corners creased. Spot near TE 9-3/4" from RE. LE: spot 5" from TE. (Box 18)
  - [The Upper Yosemite Fall], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 55; Plate Dimensions: 52 × 41 Matt Dimensions: 62 × 47 Mammoth print No visible damage. All edges cockled. BE: 1" line 7" from LE. TLC creased. Ink spot hear TLC. (Box 18)
  - [The Lower Yosemite Fall], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 56; Plate Dimensions: 52 × 41 Matt Dimensions: 62 × 47 Mammoth print Fading 1/2" along TE & RE. All edges cockled. All corners creased. RE: water(?) stain from 3-1/2" to 9-3/4" from BE, extends almost to photograph. LE: stain 1/2" from edge, 2-1/2" from BE. LE: small group of pots 8-1/4" from TE. (Box 18)
  - [The Yosemite Falls, 2630 ft], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. 51; Plate Dimensions: 52 × 41 Matt Dimensions: 62 × 47 Mammoth print No visible damage. All edges cockled. All corners slightly creased. RE: crease 3" from BE. (Box 18)
  - [Camp Grove, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. A29; Plate Dimensions: 21 × 31 Matt Dimensions: 42 × 52 (Box 1)
  - [Cathedral Rocks, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. A12; Plate Dimensions: 21 × 31 Matt Dimensions: 42 × 52 (Box 1)
  - [North Dome, Royal Arches, Washington Column], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. A44; Plate Dimensions: 21 × 31 Matt Dimensions: 42 × 52 (Box 1)
  - [Mirror View Three Brothers], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. A28; Plate Dimensions: 31 × 21 Matt Dimensions: 52 × 42 (Box 1)
  - [Mount Starr King, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. A39; Plate Dimensions: 31 × 21 Matt Dimensions: 52 × 42 (Box 1)
  - [Yosemite Falls, 2130 ft.], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. A32; Plate Dimensions: 31 × 21 Matt Dimensions: 52 × 42 (Box 1)
  - [The Sentinel, 3270 ft., Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. A24; Plate Dimensions: 31 × 21 Matt Dimensions: 52 × 42 (Box 1)
  - [The Half Dome], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. A35; Plate Dimensions: 21 × 31 Matt Dimensions: 42 × 52 (Box 1)
  - [Up the Valley, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. A18; Plate Dimensions: 21 × 31 Matt Dimensions: 42 × 52 (Box 1)
  - [The Cascade between the Vernal and Nevada Falls, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. A53; Plate Dimensions: 21 × 31 Matt Dimensions: 42 × 52 (Box 1)
  - Map of the Yosemite Valley by C. King and J.T. Gardner, [ca. 1867]; ID no. SCW147; Plate Dimensions: 21 × 31 Matt Dimensions: 42 × 52 (Box 1)
  - [The Lower Yosemite Fall], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. A34; Plate Dimensions: 31 × 21 Matt Dimensions: 52 × 42 (Box 1)
  - [El Capitan, 3600, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. A8; Plate Dimensions: 21 × 31 Matt Dimensions: 42 × 52 (Box 7)
  - [Tutocanula Pass, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. A17; Plate Dimensions: 31 × 21 Matt Dimensions: 52 × 42 (Box 1)
  - [Mt. Starr King, Yosemite], [ca. 1867]; Watkins Series no. A40; Plate Dimensions: 21 × 31 Matt Dimensions: 42 × 52 (Box 1)
  - [El Capitan], ID no. SCW80; Plate Dimensions: 15.5 × 10 Matt Dimensions: 19 × 13 (Box 1, Folder 3/5)
  - [Valley from Glacier Point], ID no. SCW81; Plate Dimensions: 15.3 × 10.2 Matt Dimensions: 19 × 13 (Box 1, Folder 4/5)
  - [El Capitan] [oval image], ID no. SCW82; Plate Dimensions: 15.3 × 10.2 Matt Dimensions: 19 × 13 (Box 1, Folder 4/5)
  - [Half Dome] [river in foreground, with Half Dome in background], ID no. SCW83; Plate Dimensions: 10.2 × 15.3 Matt Dimensions: 13 × 19 (Box 1, Folder 4/5)
  - [The Sentinel, Yosemite], ID no. SCW84; Plate Dimensions: 31.5 × 21.5 Matt Dimensions: 31.5 × 21.5 (Box 1, Folder 3/5)
  - [Half Dome] [Half Dome, bird's eye view], [1870]; ID no. SCW85; Plate Dimensions: 10.2 × 15.3 Matt Dimensions: 13 × 19 (Box 1, Folder 4/5)
  - [The Yosemite Valley from Inspiration Point], ID no. SCW86; Plate Dimensions: 21 × 31.2 Matt Dimensions: 21 × 31.2 (Box 1, Folder 3/5)
  - [El Capitan], ID no. SCW87; Plate Dimensions: 15.5 × 10 Matt Dimensions: 19 × 13 (Box 1, Folder 3/5)
  - [Yosemite Falls] [oval image], ID no. SCW88; Plate Dimensions: 15.3 × 10.2 Matt Dimensions: 19 × 13 (Box 1, Folder 4/5)
  - [View of the Valley], [1867]; Watkins Series no. [no. 100]; Plate Dimensions: 10.2 × 15.3 Matt Dimensions: 13 × 19 (Box 1, Folder 4/5)
  - [Tree: Grizzly Giant, Man: Galen Clark], [1867]; Watkins Series no. [no. 113]; Plate Dimensions: 15.5 × 10 Matt Dimensions: 19 × 13 (Box 1, Folder 3/5)
  - [Yosemite Falls] [falls framed by two trees in foreground], [1867]; Watkins Series no. [no. 51]; Plate Dimensions: 15.3 × 10.2 Matt Dimensions: 19 × 13 (Box 1, Folder 4/5)
  - [Yosemite Falls] [Yosemite Book, Plate 10], ID no. SCW91 copy; Plate Dimensions: 23.6 × 18.1 Copy (not original) (Box 1, Folder 3/5)
  - [Yosemite from Inspiration Point], [1867]; Watkins Series no. [no. 6]; Plate Dimensions: 10.2 × 15.3 Matt Dimensions: 13 × 19 (Box 1, Folder 4/5)
  - [Mount Starr King], [1867]; Watkins Series no. [no. 69]; Plate Dimensions: 15.3 × 10.2 Matt Dimensions: 19 × 13 (Box 1, Folder 4/5)
  - Bridal Veil, 900 Feet, Yosemite Watkins' New Series, Yosemite and Pacific Coast, 26 New Montgomery St. uner Palace Hotel, S.F., Watkins Series no. B7; Matt Dimensions: 14 × 22 (Box 1, Folder 3/5)
  - Half Dome and Washington Column, Yosemite. Watkins' New Series, Yosemite and Pacific Coast, 26 New Montgomery St. uner Palace Hotel, S.F., Watkins Series no. B26; Matt Dimensions: 14 × 22 Boudoir card (Box 1, Folder 4/5)
  - The dead giant, Tuolumne Grove, 30 feet, 8 inches in diameter. Watkins' New Series, Yosemite and Pacific Coast, 26 New Montgomery St. uner Palace Hotel, S.F., Watkins Series no. B3090; Matt Dimensions: 14 × 22 Boudoir card (Box 1, Folder 4/5)
  - Mirror View of the Half Dome, Yosemite. Watkins' New Series, Yosemite and Pacific Coast, 26 New Montgomery St. uner Palace Hotel, S.F., Watkins Series no. B3129; Matt Dimensions: 14 × 22 Boudoir card (Box 1, Folder 4/5)
  - [Nevada Falls], ID no. SCW98; Matt Dimensions: 16.5 × 10.5 Cabinet card (Box 1, Folder 3/5)
  - [Bridal Veil, Yosemite 900 ft.], ID no. SCW99; Plate Dimensions: 32.4 × 21.2 Matt Dimensions: 32.4 × 21.2 Cabinet card (Box 1, Folder 3/5)